samknows.com 2015-09-19

# Privacy | SamKnows

If you have any questions or concerns about SamKnows' Privacy Policy or data protection, please contact us at [team@samknows.com](mailto:team@samknows.com).

**Your privacy is important to SamKnows. Please take a moment to read our Privacy Policy, which governs the use of the samknows.com website, and let us know if you have any questions.**

#### Collection and Use of Personal Information

Personal information is data that can be used to uniquely identify a single person. We may collect your personal information, such as your name and email address when, for example, you sign-up to receive our exchange updates and regular website updates.

When you volunteer to be a panelist for a broadband measurement project, you will be subject to the specific Privacy Policy for that project.

SamKnows strongly believes in the importance of keeping users' personal information private. SamKnows will never use your information for any use beyond that stated or the permissions given to us.

#### Disclosure to Third Parties

SamKnows will not share your personal details with third parties, unless you have granted us explicit permission to do. It may however become necessary - by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence - for SamKnows to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our operations or users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the relevant third party.

#### Protection of Personal Information

SamKnows takes administrative, technical, and physical precautions to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

#### User broadband tools

If you carry out an availability check, exchange location check or use our mapping engine, we will only use your location, postcode or phone number entered for the purpose of carrying out that check and further checks of your line. This information is essential to find out which services are available to you. Phone numbers and postcodes may be cached for the purposes of performing faster checks should someone check with the same or similar details, but these will be stored for a maximum of fourteen days only.

#### Server logs and cookies

SamKnows collects information about users visiting our website by analyzing site traffic, which includes the use of cookies and server logs. The cookie itself does not contain personal information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can alter your browser settings to prevent automatic acceptance, if you prefer. If you opt not to receive our cookies, we cannot guarantee that your experience with our website will be as quick or responsive as if you do receive cookies.

#### Your data

Users of SamKnows.com have certain rights under your country?s Data Protection Legislation. You can, for instance, ask to be told what information we hold about you in our databases. SamKnows will provide you with all of the details that we hold about you, both online and offline, upon request. In order to request this information, please contact us by sending an email to [team@samknows.com](mailto:team@samknows.com).

#### Changes to this policy

SamKnows may update this Privacy Policy from time to time as we add new products and services, as we improve our current offerings, and as technologies change. Any changes will be highlighted along with the updated Privacy Policy.
